<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Young Fenimore Lee</title>
  <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2019-08-23T03:56:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://slinky773.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Young Fenimore Lee</name>
    <email>yflee7@students.d125.org</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Waiting For This Day to End</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2019/02/07/Waiting-For-This-Day-to-End.html"/>
    <updated>2019-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2019/02/07/Waiting For This Day to End</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;waiting-for-this-day-to-end&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Waiting For This Day to End&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;25 Nov 2018 - Stanford, CA - 18:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And language just happened, it was never planned;&lt;br /&gt;
And it’s inadequate to describe where I am:&lt;br /&gt;
In the room of my house, where the light’s never been,&lt;br /&gt;
Waiting for this day to end…”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll put an epigraph where a pen ought to be, and it’ll all be alright. I live in sincere genuflection, a kneel in pooling light to whirling, vortical forces just barely out of view; and such and such always manages to smooth the routine malaise of the typical reader. Take your time; make it easy; maybe sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of my work, I’ll say nothing, for there is nothing to say; and of my work, I’ll say nothing, for there is nothing to say. What could there be? All to be found is already found. We all know it, too: the freezing mornings when lightless taxis leave you to walk home alone, the loneliness of feeling half-past dead walking into Nazareth, un chien andalusia, and une anée sans lumière. What more can there be, besides these terse quakes pushed through others’ spirits out of our own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. And so, I stay silent. I sit on my bed, gaze up at the raucous clock, and wait for this day to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The night they drove old Dixie down,&lt;br /&gt;
And all the bells were ringin’;&lt;br /&gt;
The night they drove old Dixie down,&lt;br /&gt;
And all the people were singin’; they went,&lt;br /&gt;
La la, na-na na-na-na-nah:&lt;br /&gt;
La-la-na-na, na-na-na-nah…”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after Chester Bennington died, I reflected on the fact that you could put the end of a belt between a dorm door and the frame, and it would hang limply, and would not fall: a comforting constancy for some, an unsettling devil under the bed for me, one that would never arise again, but which seemed to haunt the phantasmic space curving around the brown edges of the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Night They Drove Old Dixie Down” is a song by The Band. It’s sung from the perspective of Virgil Caine, a civil war railway worker, who becomes a farmer after George Stoneman’s Union army destroys the Confederate supply lines. Virgil laments the dismantling of his beloved home country fields, the death of his brother, and the failure of a cause he refuses to fully relinquish. On that night, at the close of the war, as the church bells rang in the orange glow of lanterns out on the the horizon, all Virgil heard was the mourning of the south and, unbeknownst to him, the victory of the freed slave; la, nah na-na na-na-na-nah. Does Virgil know about the glory of emancipation? Can he hear the bells of celebration?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst blindness, he may never know. And so, as railroads are reassembled, he and his kin continue to toil under an evil so great some may never see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Tears of rage, tears of grief;&lt;br /&gt;
Why must I always be the thief?&lt;br /&gt;
Come to me now, you know we’re so alone –&lt;br /&gt;
And life is brief…”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, the heart is filled with gold, as if it was a purse. We are raised by the great Mother Mary, who came to Anselm Kiefer at age 6 with a visage like a painting. She never appeared to me. At age 8, through the haze of misty willow trees drooping in the afternoon air, I saw a ghostly face breathing, blinking. It filled my heart, and I felt my veins freezing into statuette veins that would thaw in the heat of a summer night where I would boil, stutter, and die alongside the beautiful, benevolent Mary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mother Mary will surely come to me tomorrow. It is our destiny. She will come to Virgil as well, as pure a spirit as I can think of. Virgil, that infinite symbol of beauty. His system is as incommensurable as any other. His values are clear. He swears, by the mud beneath his feet, that a Caine will fight to the death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun has come out from behind the clouds, and light has arrived upon the window beside my bed. La la, nah-nah nah-nah-nah-nah. I sing to the tune of the morning carillon. The sun arising is a special glory, the same glory as the night they drove old Dixie down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What seems always certain is music, like the music of the morning bells, or the heart that fills with gold. A friend of mine likes to gesture to some album covers and explain that, when he stays holed up in his room for days on end, “these are my best friends.” Mother Mary came to me one day in auditory form; I once heard her whisper into my ear on an early morning, after waking out of breath, hearing my panting echo ceaselessly, and suddenly, I heard her speak to me: “Come to me now, you know we’re so alone, and life is brief.” Another day, perhaps I will hear those eternal words: “The night they drove old Dixie down.” And another: “I will lay me down, I will ease your mind.” Those remarks are perhaps all that remain eternal in a vortex of flux and harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds are eternal once transfixed into the imagination, thus becoming irreplaceable as a true index of a time, place, and stillness. Sounds are endless once heard; that fading echo is illusory. Mother Mary stays with me wherever I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, Mary, come to me one time more. Tell me what you know, who has known you, who is saved and who is not; please, remind me to mind the gap, to not clutch the ledge, to hold on, to eat, to sleep, to wash up; please, save me, though I cannot believe; and perhaps then, God will look upon me and wonder whether to save a soul in disbelief twice, or only once and never again. Like they say: Gloria in Excelsis Deo. Jesus died for somebody’s sins, but not mine. Mother Mary stays with me, and she told me her name. And her name is g-l-o-r-i… g-l-o-r-i-a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLORIA. G-L-O-R-I-A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLORIA. G-L-O-R-I-A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLORIA. G-L-O-R-I-A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;G L O R I A . G - L - O - R - I - A .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Die Meistersinger</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2018/09/25/Die-Meistersinger.html"/>
    <updated>2018-09-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2018/09/25/Die Meistersinger</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;die-meistersinger&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Die Meistersinger&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;25 Sep 2018 - Stanford, CA - 18:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandfather escaped from North Korea in the midst of the Korean war when he realized the danger of staying in the village where he lived. Quietly, in the middle of the night, he dragged a boat to the water with two other young men from his town, and they alone, family-less, set away. He arrived in what would become South Korea, and worked in labor camps, the typical but tragic way to eat, drink, and tenuously tread water during post-war reconstruction. After some time, he became an important freight-forwarding business owner. I have magazines on my bookshelf with his wry, dry smile on the covers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father, his eldest son, wanted to play music rather than anything else. Before long, my grandfather found out, and tore up all of his music books. My sister anthologized this event in our reconstructed family history with a simple imagined declaration: “It is not a man’s job to play music.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father listened to &lt;em&gt;Die Meistersinger&lt;/em&gt;, a Wagner opera about guild singers from antiquity, in our house when we were growing up. After a little while longer, I learned about the Nazi’s love of Wagner’s music. My father listening to &lt;em&gt;Die Meistesinger&lt;/em&gt;, Nazis burning paintings: a sort of Stockholm Syndrome tied to banning art that followed our family from Korea to Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a painting in the SFMOMA by Anselm Kiefer with the words “Die Meistersinger” scrawled at the top. It’s a blue painting of a field, with the canvas covered in straw. The clumps of straw that sit atop the paint are protrusions sagging out, like herniated sacs. Straw becomes organs, spilling out of itself and gushing red paint into other parts; straw creates autonomy, crafted through bloodless flesh. I look off to the horizon of the field. Circles of red and white lie silent next to phantasmic black splotches that float out of the canvas and into the air besides the straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These clumps were &lt;em&gt;die meistersinger&lt;/em&gt;. They burned in secret and sang in the tempo marking &lt;em&gt;langsam und schmachtend&lt;/em&gt;, which, my dad explained to me once, translates to slow and languishing. They performed in theaters as, elsewhere, what my father cherished was removed, slow and languishing, from memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father was &lt;em&gt;der meistersinger&lt;/em&gt;. In one dream I have, I see the painting, my father’s face within the straw. He furrows his brows, as he always does, and 12 limbs of yellow stalk rupture from his body. He screeches, like a Francis Bacon painting, vaults towards me, and the last thing I see before awaking is blood, in the same red color as what hides behind the numbered cardboard of the painting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>
