<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Young Fenimore Lee</title>
  <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-20T01:01:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>https://slinky773.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Young Fenimore Lee</name>
    <email>yflee7@students.d125.org</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Rick and Morty</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2016/12/20/where%3F%3F%3F.html"/>
    <updated>2016-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2016/12/20/where???</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;rick-and-morty&quot;&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;20 Dec 2016 - Buffalo Grove, Illinois - 00:49&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is Season 3 of Rick and Morty?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHERE?!?!???!?&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Why.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Morty: Why???&quot; style=&quot;width: 35em; margin: 1em 7.5em 0.5em 7.5em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Why am I not on TV, like, right now? Why? WHY? WHY?!?!?!??&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fin&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ceci n’est pas une histoire</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2016/10/01/power-of-story.html"/>
    <updated>2016-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2016/10/01/power-of-story</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ceci-nest-pas-une-histoire&quot;&gt;Ceci n’est pas une histoire&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 Oct 2016 - Buffalo Grove, Illinois - 02:04&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OK, so it turns out trying to watch a movie a day is a huge time sink. I did it for about a week and a half, but eventually couldn’t handle the time. Whoops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even writing about all of the films I mentioned in the last blog post was hard. There’s a lot to discuss in all of those films. They all ended up being very good, with these ratings:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Princess Momonoke: 9.5/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Lebowski: 7.5/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drive: 9.5/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upstream Color: 8.5/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apocalypse Now: 9/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Third Man: 9/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goldfinger: 6.5/10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So yeah, they were all really great films (except, Goldfinger, eh…). I’ll hopefully be able to write my thoughts on all of them, but in the meantime, here’s an essay I wrote about stories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have to distill experience into pure emotion. In The Sound and the Fury, piecing together the sequence of events really isn’t as important as understanding, well, the sound and the fury. Who knew.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all Benjy in some sense. We all experience life as a fluid, a cup of water sloshing to the rim and finally spilling all over the table, falling in perfect droplets. Time and sense are fragile, surface tension broken with a touch. It all moves from one place to another just as easily as the water does.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing that really matters is the truth it gives you, distilled in the wine it transforms into. Drink up and feel yourself filled with the emotion an entire spectrum of sensations have clumped themselves into. That is what a story is.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 2nd, 2005, Katie Flynn was in a limousine with her mother, Jennifer, plus some other relatives. They had just left a family wedding. Katie was one of the flower girls.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Katie’s aunt and uncle were getting married, Martin Heidgen was drinking up, preparing to gracefully end Katie’s life. He drove for two miles down the wrong side of the highway at 70 mph until his car collided with the front of the limousine. In the collision, Katie’s seatbelt decapitated her. Jennifer was the only one to make it out of the limousine unscathed. She picked up Katie’s bloody head, walked off to the side of the road, and sat there while emergency responders dissected the limousine to salvage family members.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They salvaged the rest of Katie’s body. Sometimes I imagine Katie’s soul lying in the bottom of the limousine, a silhouette dressed in white condemned to young death eternally. Never again would she walk to see her mother’s loving face, or any of the people she loved that were now climbing out of the limousine. Maybe she looked up and saw her mother’s tears drip onto her face. Or maybe she was still in the limousine. Or maybe she was just dead.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the basis for the song Limousine by early 2000’s band Brand New. The song is sung from Jennifer’s perspective. “Remain in my hands and smile,” she begs. The voice and words are laced with pain, a spiked cocktail that’s one part tragedy and three parts calm angst; we drink up to hear Jennifer Flynn, mother to a joyful flower girl alive just hours earlier; but never again, never again. “Remain in my hands and smile.” She runs her hands through black seven-year-old hair like she would have just three hours ago; just one hour ago; just a half hour; just then, when she was sitting right beside her in a limousine. But never again will it feel the way it did.
Suddenly, the noise fades, and we’re taken to the perspective of Heidgen the killer:     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hey you beauty supreme,
Yeah, you were right about me.
But can I get myself out from underneath,
This guilt that will crush me?

And in the choir,
I saw our sad messiah.
He was bored and tired of my laments.
He said, “I died for you one time,
But never again.”    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song becomes remarkably plaintive. The D-A-G-E chord progression underlies the imagery of a man kneeled down in the pew of a chapel, looking up at the cross and hearing those tragic words: that “I died for you one time,/but never again.” Never again. Never again. Never again.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I listened to the song, the words rung in my ears. There was some sort of torment and guilt behind the ringing, the same that I suppose Heidgen felt. Guilt was appropriated into the mind through shock. “And in the choir…” Jesus stood before me. I saw his stigmata drip blood onto the hardwood floor of my room. “I died for you one time,/but never again.”    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the song is a flurry of distorted guitar over the words Jennifer said to the media two days after the accident:    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;We’ll never have to buy adjacent plots of earth,
We’ll never have to rot together under the dirt.
I’ll never have to lose my baby in the crowd…

Well, I should be laughing right now.    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song sputters to an end, arpeggios on B and G chords slowing to a halt. The story closes just as it began: in silence.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He was bored and tired of my laments.” A sigh. I watched Jesus’s eyes glaze over, staring at the pathetic sight that lay before him. I gazed back, and said, “Well, I should be laughing now…”    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Song and music provided my first experiences with the full power of storytelling. I grew up with two musicians for parents, so I listened to WFMT radio in the car, knew the names of a few famous conductors and composers, and watched Fantasia 2000 on DVD. I was particularly captivated with the segment on The Sorcerer’s Apprentice, set to the tone poem of the same name by Paul Dukas. Mickey Mouse is the titular character, blundering about with his master’s hat, creating chaos everywhere until the master eventually comes back to set things straight. The master reprimands Mickey and hits him on the back with a broom in time with a final run in the violins and a chord from the entire orchestra.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music can be programmatic, following a narrative, but more times than not the most important aspect of music is emotion, not chronology. Every conductor has said at one point the equivalent of Victor Hugo’s quote, “Music expresses that which cannot be put into words and that which cannot remain silent.” I can describe chord progressions and patterns in music all I want, but texture? Timbre? These are intuitive, but ineffable. Once a poem has become set to music, once every single feeling, fabric, sense possible has been brought into the realm of the transcendent, it becomes that much greater. One destroys the constructs that scaffold up a poem - phrase constructions, diction, ink on a paper - to create something that goes beyond.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider Limousine, where perspective shifts between people narrating trauma. Do you need to piece together the sequence of events in the lyrics to understand the anguish? Consider The Sorcerer’s Apprentice. Can you feel the slowing momentum building to the moment when you feel the broom hit your own head, like I did?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Narrative finds its power at its most nonsensical and unreal. A story is never actually a story; it’s never quite straightforward, never quite with crystal clear meaning. Story evolves, shifts between people and cultures. It transforms with every reading, consensus on interpretation oscillating constantly. It can be everything; but set in stone?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never again. The truth in a story is in the wine, not the water. Water is transparent; when you look through it, you realize that it’s empty. It’s the destruction of all that makes water water that allows it to transform into full bodied wine. And the only way you can taste it is realize that water is clear, inherently nothing. Like a story.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to films and videos from a very young age, too. I had my own computer ever since elementary school, plus access to plenty of DVDs. I wasn’t ever truly conscious of filmmaking techniques until much later in life - character development, cinematography, architecture of a shot, close-ups, wide angles, match shots, and all the other parts of clever editing - but I did develop a fascination with the medium. If a piece of literature brings an event or place to life, film brings them to hyperreality. That which can only exist in the mind, no longer merely exists there anymore: it’s in an external realm, beyond mind and body.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite films is Paprika, an animated film by Satoshi Kon. An uncommon film to hear about, since the behemoth of serious Japanese animation is Miyazaki, but Kon was just as incredible as he ever was, if not better. In Paprika, the world rapidly shifts between reality and what is a dream world, instabilities and all. Kon cleverly uses match shots - close graphic matches two different scenes - to quickly bring the viewer between the two worlds. One moment, a character is in reality, picking up a cup of coffee - now he’s picking up a mug in a dream. And then another dream. And another, until the film is now shifting between five different dreams worlds. Or eight. Or whatever.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kon uses these fast shifts between what is real and what is not at such breakneck speed that the film eventually blurs to the point where it’s unclear whether one is in reality or in the dream world at any given moment. The question is whether that actually matters. Perhaps the best way to experience the film is to surrender yourself to the confusion. I know that I gave up tracking chronology, and I surrendered, letting the surreality wash over me. Such surrender is an abstraction from chronology, after which there is no escape. I watched the world destroying itself; streets being pulled up and ripped apart; a absurd topsy turvy carnival. Did this happen in the real world, or in a dream? I didn’t care.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annihilation of chronology, sense, and all ordinary conception of narrative, in the end, becomes the only constant, the only real reliability in interpretation. The only consistency is the lack of it, but that’s natural; after all, ceci n’est pas une histoire.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of art, I would assert, follows this very rule: they create stories, but the annihilation of any inherent meaning or chronology frees it from the confines of a creator’s original conception. A creator, it is claimed, imbues a work of art with meaning and intention; but this, in itself, is an abstraction upon the mere fact that a creator creates notes on a page, or visual images, or sound, and then leaves it alone, to be recreated every time it’s experienced anew.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All conceptions of art, all interpretation, is an abstraction. Consider The Treachery of Images by René Magritte. “Ceci n’est pas une pipe.” This is not a pipe. A depiction of a pipe, Magritte posits, is not a pipe. If you look at the painting on a computer screen, you are not looking at a pipe. In both cases, you are seeing color; the real painting uses pigment, and the computer screen uses RGB dots. In either case, pieced together as gestalt it appears as a pipe, but the reality is that it is not. It is an abstraction of ink, or dots, or pigment, or whatever medium it uses to create a visual of…    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. It is nothing. Ceci n’est pas une pipe. I came to terms with the fact that I had an emotional response to nothing. I ignored interpretation, and let myself annihilate all prior conceptions of what a piece was, or could be. I let it wash over, cleansing the word “art” from our superimposed naïveté. The true experience in story is an abstraction, but not an abstraction from the picture - it’s an abstraction from the dots on the canvas, the pure truth, that permits the real truth to come out in art.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it looks nice. The composition is pretty. Magritte made the red tiled roofs provide a contrast to the geometric pattern of falling bowler hat men.”    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Ceci n’est pas une pipe. Ceci n’est pas une histoire. Ceci n’est pas. It is not.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-weight: 500&quot;&gt;•&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many thanks to Brand New, James Algar, Walt Disney Pictures, René Magritte, and countless other artists for providing stories that have been central to my life.&lt;/em&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rest in Peace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Satoshi Kon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;August 24, 2010&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Watching Movies</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2016/03/01/watching-movies.html"/>
    <updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2016/03/01/watching-movies</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;watching-movies&quot;&gt;Watching Movies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 Mar 2016 - Buffalo Grove, Illinois - 21:04&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops. It has been forever since my last post. Now I’m just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/superlative.png&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s okay, I’m going to have material to last quite a while. Reason being, I’ve decided to start watching one movie every day! I got that idea from watching a lot of video essays from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/everyframeapainting&quot;&gt;Tony Zhou’s Every Frame a Painting&lt;/a&gt; and thinking about all the films I haven’t had the time to watch. Then, I watched a couple of movies with my friend to compensate. It wasn’t a big stretch from there to “watch a movie every day.” Sorta.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I have rewatched Spirited Away and Watership Down, plus watched Millennium Actress and Paprika, both by Japanese filmmaker Satoshi Kon. I’ll give a quick rundown on my thoughts. No spoilers here. I promise.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spirited Away: 9.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an incredibly hyped up film, but I think it deserves it. To summarize the plot, the protagonist, Chihiro, and her family move into town and stumble upon an abandoned amusement park. Chihiro’s parents discover a buffet, gorge themselves on the endless of food on the table, and get turned into pigs by the witch that runs the nearby bathhouse. Day turns to night, and the amusement park transforms into a spirit world, trapping Chihiro in; Chihiro embarks on a journey to escape the amusement park and save her parents from the slaughterhouse.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a tour de force that showcases Miyazaki’s unique talent of creating expansive, immersive universes. The setting only encompasses the bathhouse and a short train ride to a house nearby, but that still manages to make the world feel extensive, stretching far and wide; it’s just a bathhouse, but it’s bigger on the inside.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other standout aspects of the movie are the excellent score, composed by Studio Ghibli regular Joe Hisaishi, and the animation, just as impeccable as the rest of the Miyazaki/Studio Ghibli films. The animation reflects a childlike, caricatured, and beautiful world, befitting of Miyazaki’s storytelling.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t much to say that hasn’t already been said by many others, considering the movie’s status as an Oscar winner. tl;dr it’s a must-see.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/spirited-away.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spirited Away&quot; style=&quot;width: 35em; margin: 1em 7.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watership Down: 7/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based off the Richard Adams children’s novel, this is a movie about a group of rabbits who discover their warren is in some sort of strange danger and venture off to find a new home. Like the novel, it’s an allegory for government systems, with each warren the group discovers being organized (or ruled) a different way.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/watership-down.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Watership Down&quot; style=&quot;width: 35em; margin: 1em 7.5em 0.5em 7.5em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bun buns&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rewatched the film, and it wasn’t as good on the second viewing as it felt on the first. The standout aspect of the story was the portrayal of the rabbits’ belief system, presented through the introduction and the rabbits’ dialogues. Like other allegorical tales, it uses spare words to create inward resonance, which is where the film’s power comes from. On second viewing, though, the dialogue began to seem pithy and forceful, diminishing the film’s overall effect.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there are nice moments. The especially powerful ones, for me, are the ones involving the Black Rabbit of Inlé. Longtime lovers of the book series are pretty attached to one quote in particular, said by the god of the rabbit world, Frith: “All the world will be your enemy, Prince with a Thousand Enemies, and whenever they catch you, they will kill you. But first they must catch you, digger, listener, runner, prince with the swift warning. Be cunning and full of tricks and your people shall never be destroyed.”    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation itself is also pretty nice. I liked looking at the watercolor-like backgrounds. It makes you feel like you’re looking at a painting in every frame. The actual character animations felt a little lacking, though.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millennium Actress: 6.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paprika: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Millennium Actress and Paprika were made by Satoshi Kon, possibly the second most famous Japanese animated filmmaker behind Miyazaki. Kon’s style revolves around his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oz49vQwSoTE&quot;&gt;distinctive editing&lt;/a&gt;, which utilizes cuts that warp both space and time. Most of them are match cuts, Kon’s farovite mean of transportation. For details, watch the previously-linked-to video essay by Tony Zhou on Kon’s work.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This warping of space and time suits the narrative Kon wishes to draw. As Tony describes in his video essay, Kon’s films draw dichotomies between the different identities of their characters, whether that be onscreen-offscreen (Millennium Actress) or waking-dreaming (Paprika). The match cuts draw these comparisons literally seamlessly; without even realizing it’s happening; instantaneously, within just a few frames.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://otakufilms.files.wordpress.com/2015/02/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Paprika Fascinating Cut&quot; style=&quot;width: 35em; margin: 1em 7.5em 0.5em 7.5em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Holy…&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kon’s style makes for interesting, and sometimes confusing, experiences. For both of these films, I couldn’t keep track of exactly what was going on anywhere beyond the initial exposition. In both films, there are two different worlds you’re seeing at any given moment, with the edits transporting you between them; but after a while, the movies seem to be mixing the two worlds together, making it virtually impossible to actually distinguish which one you’re seeing. Or maybe it’s possible, and I just wasn’t paying close enough attention while watching these two films. In any case, the films definitely suggest a fading distinction between the two worlds as time goes on, so I found that trying to piece together what was going on was actually detrimental to enjoying the film. I ended up just letting the narrative unfold and appreciating the movie that way. The conclusion of the films both solidly established what ended up happening altogether, so it all made sense in the end.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, time to talk about the specifics on the movies. I watched Millennium Actress first. Synopsis: The frame story is an old actress being interviewed after a keepsake of hers, a small key, was found at a torn-down movie studio. The actress takes the interviewers on her life story that is told switching between the stories of the films she acted in and her chase for her true love, an anti-government rebel she bumped into by chance on the street, and who gave her the aforementioned key and told her they’d meet again.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, the way the story is crafted blends the two stories together until they feel like one. It was interesting and done well, but so much of the narrative was fueled by melodramatic Japanese period dramas, making it decidedly less than captivating. The period drama feel was clearly what the movie was aiming for, considering it was following an actress from those films, but it ended up just being full of exhausted clichés, almost uncomfortably silly at some points. The third act of the movie made up for it, but I didn’t enjoy a lot of the second act for those reasons.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/millennium-actress.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Millennium Actress&quot; style=&quot;width: 35em; margin: 1em 7.5em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I watched Paprika, a whole other monster. Synopsis: Scientists working with a device that allows for access into other people’s dreams find that a prototype has been stolen. The thief is wreaking havoc upon the minds of innocent people by driving them insane through their dreams. The thief has even managed to make it into the minds of waking people. The scientists try to remedy the situation, but are circumvented by constant waking dreams they can’t escape.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, the whole movie feels like one big dream, which is simultaneously absolutely terrifying and incredible to watch. (see the earlier gif) The story and execution was all incredible. The way Kon blends everything into one big cacophony of realities is pretty perfect. It’s not completely comprehensible, but it’s certainly captivating in a way that Millennium Actress wasn’t. A must see, in my opinion.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s my thoughts on the movies I watched these past few days. If you’re interested in the movies I’m watching next:    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Princess Mononoke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Big Lebowski&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;s&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/s&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JK, Drive&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upstream Color (by Shane Carruth who made Primer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;s&gt;The Green Mile&lt;/s&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;JK, Apocalypse Now&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Third Man&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goldfinger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bad Sleep Well (a Kurosawa film)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what I’ll be talking about in my next blog. See you all then!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Hopeful Epiphany</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2015/02/01/hopeful-epiphany.html"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2015/02/01/hopeful-epiphany</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This post is relic of a time gone by. It’s a little strange, and I don’t think the way I did in this post anymore, but the ideas I came up with before are still a part of me, so I hope this is, at the very least, somewhat interesting.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-hopeful-epiphany&quot;&gt;A Hopeful Epiphany&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 Feb 2015 - Buffalo Grove, Illinois - 6:34 AM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week ago, I had an epiphany. The epiphany was that I (myself, not anyone else) should live my life according to the maxim “live life for others.”    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the kind of philosopher that I hate the most - a romanticist philosopher. My thought is constantly driven by emotions, rather than rigorous logic. It’s natural for humans to be so, but in philosophy, this is a death sentence (in my opinion, anyway). How are you ever going to come up with logical reason if whatever reasoning you come up with is produced by emotion? Emotion will never be the origin of complete objectivity. Philosophy is supposed to be driven through complete objectivity. These things cannot coexist.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Disclaimer: these are my own opinions about what philosophy truly is. Not real philosophers. :P)    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, this maxim I produced was intended to be how all people should live. It was produced out of thin air, as I sat in my room, deep in sad thought. Nothing actually happened recently, but I was feeling sorrowful. Obviously a product of my adolescent mind, wired to go haywire in mood constantly. It was in this mood that I thought about the prospect of people living their lives for others. I then formed the statement you saw above as a categorical imperative - my own version of Kant’s universal laws.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So obviously, not exactly an objectively great categorical imperative. But my process for creating my own philosophy is to produce these statements and analyze them with a reasoned mind. After all, it might actually be well reasoned (somehow).    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why I haven’t turned into a purely logical mind is because that romanticist part of my brain is absolutely necessary to stay human. If I decided to make myself act in purely logical ways, I’m certain I would begin to devolve. I would lose any sense of personality. My peers would quickly begin to hate me.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Romanticism is who I am as a human. Philosophy is who I am beyond that.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after analyzing what I came up with this time, I decided that it should truly be called a maxim because I decided it shouldn’t apply to anyone other than myself. It seems to only be a good way to live for myself. And here’s my reasoning:    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have grown up, I have developed into a person who essentially lives for the approval of others. It’s something innate, and I don’t think I could change that, nor would I want to. It has come to define who I am. I essentially derive pleasure in life from company and approval from others.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this has come to mean that basically, I love to brag about myself. I enjoy the pointless tauting of accomplishments that, in the eyes of the uninitiated, are impressive, and in the eyes of the knowledgeable, are not even close to impressive. It has become a selfish and pointless thing, to live to impress others. It has led to nearly no direction in life. Even if impressing people made me happy, it seemed like there really wasn’t a point to it all.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even worse was the fact that since I have never innately cared about doing things for myself, for purely self satisfaction, I really never did anything at all. Sure, I care about eating, and sleeping (sometimes), but when it came to ambition, I have never really been able to be satisfied through myself. It was all just for bragging - the only satisfaction I gained was when others approved of it. After finishing something on my own, without evaluation from others, I innately solely worry about what others think of it. Is it according to others’ standards? Is this truly good? Or am I just in over my head? And after I realized how pointless it was to live in that way, without a direction, eventually I just did nothing at all.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has to be a different way of living, right?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m never going to be able to change my habit of needing social interaction and approval to be happy. At least, I shouldn’t count on it. It’s very well ingrained inside of me - so far ingrained that I have doubts about whether I can change it. And I’m sure that even if I was able to, if I tried to change myself so drastically, it would be damaging to myself.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why not embrace this habit of instinct? Why not change my mindset about what I do to take advantage of the fact that I naturally gravitate towards other people?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what my new maxim is. It’s me embracing that mindset and even making it into something noble. Now, whenever I think about what I am doing, I think about everything in terms of benefitting others, not myself. It’s what I have always wanted to do, anyway - break off the pointlessness of the past and care solely about others. And that’s not altruistic or godly - it’s human. For me, anyway. That’s just how I am.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others aren’t. That’s okay. Don’t live like I do if you don’t want to, or can’t. This is just how I have decided to do things.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The New Year's Resolution</title>
    <link href="https://slinky773.github.io/2015/01/01/new-year's.html"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>https://slinky773.github.io/2015/01/01/new-year's</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This post is relic of a time gone by. It’s a little strange, and I don’t think the way I did in this post anymore, but the ideas I came up with before are still a part of me, so I hope this is, at the very least, somewhat interesting.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-new-years-resolution&quot;&gt;The New Year’s Resolution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;01 Jan 2015 - Buffalo Grove, Illinois - 2:00 AM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of new year’s day, I think of a lot of broken promises. Every year, people systematically make promises and break them. They say that they will quit smoking this year. That they will stop drinking this year. Eat healthier. Start going to the gym. Stop procrastinating. Etcetera, etcetera, etcetera.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for most people, this seems to go on &lt;em&gt;ad infinitum&lt;/em&gt;. The same promises are made year after year. People remember the resolution they made last year and resolve to truly realize their goals &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; year. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; year, things will be different. After all, things &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to improve some time, right?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong. Things never &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to change. You can easily stay the same for your entire life, so long as no one has to care about you.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us take the example of the neurotic alcoholic. You may never be forced to actually stop drinking. Unless you’re such a drunk that you cause car accidents and mayhem everywhere, you could just be left to yourself in an apartment by yourself for your entire life, abandoned by your family because you couldn’t stop ruining the lives of your loved ones. They wouldn’t have to care about you. After that, unless you ruin the lives of everyone else in your proximity, no one has to care.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is strictly hypothetical, but the point is that it’s a very real possibility that &lt;strong&gt;no one cares about you&lt;/strong&gt;. So who’s going to do it? Who’s going to make you change?    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is the only one who is guaranteed to care so much about you as to make you change. Yep. You.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re the person who, like me, resolves the same time of every year to change the same flaws, realize (as I just did) that unless you really decide to change, things never will.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, do not take this to mean that things will &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; change. Things don’t have to change, but that doesn’t mean they can’t. You can change them.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just don’t expect things to happen by themselves.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have realized this just recently. My goal of success has been a work in progress over the past several years of my life. I continue to prioritize what I think is important over what is actually important. I continue to prioritize my friends, online forums, and coding projects over my schoolwork and academics. I obviously realize the importance of the latter, but have yet to figure out how I will eventually force myself to take them more seriously.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next year is the year I make myself change. Not because change is inevitable, but because change is &lt;em&gt;feasible&lt;/em&gt;. It’s not impossible to change.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not impossible to change.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not impossible.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>
